Rah For The Engineers! research matierals, 1921-1987
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Rah For The Engineers! research material, 1921-1987
AZ 521
McCormick, James P.
The bulk of this collection consists of correspondence, interviews, and reminiscences, with faculty, alumni, and students of the College of Engineering. The papers relate the personalities, projects, and growth of the College during its first century of existence. The majority of these materials were collected by McCormick between 1984 and 1986, and were used in his book Rah for the Engineers! research material
1.5 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
James P. McCormick was born in 1911 and attended Northwestern University (PhD 1937). He was an English professor at Wayne State Univertsity, and, later, an administrator for Detroit Edison Company. He retired to Tucson in 1974 and accepted a position as adjunct professor of engineering at the University of Arizona.
Organization
This collection is organized into four series:
Series I: Correspondence and Interviews, 1982-1987
Series II: Photographs, 1925-1980s
Series III: Research Notes, 1921-1986
Series IV: Monographs, 1986
Scope and Content Note
The bulk of this collection consists of correspondence, interviews, and reminiscences, with faculty, alumni, and students of the College of Engineering. The papers relate the personalities, projects, and growth of the College during its first century of existence. The majority of these materials were collected by McCormick between 1984 and 1986, and were used in his book Rah For The Engineers! research material
Access Terms
McCormick, James P.
University of Arizona -- History
University of Arizona -- Students
University of Arizona -- Faculty
Correspondence
Photographs
Container List
- Series I: Correspondence and Interviews, 1982-1987
  Contains mostly personal reminiscences and interviews by McCormick of students, deans and faculty of the college from the 1920s to the 1980s. The narratives describe personal companionships, professional associations, relationships with the professors, financial and intellectual challenges to the students, and their evaluations of higher education.
  - Correspondence and interviews with students. 1920s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 1-9)
  - E.S. Borgquist student correspondence. 1927-1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence and interviews with faculty. 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence and interviews with David Hall. 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - University of Arizona Engineering Council. 1984 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Student papers. 1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - General correspondence: book project. 1982-1987 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Series II: Photographs, 1925-1980s
  Mostly black and white photographs of activities, faculty, facilities, and students at the College. Of interest are several views, ca. 1920s, of the Saint Patrick's Day Parade, an annual outings sponsored by students.
  - Photographs. 1925-1980s (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Series III: Research Notes, 1921-1986
  Includes graphs, charts, speeches, memos, handwritten interviews, drafts of text, clippings, correspondence, and departmental reports, including "Academics in the College of Engineering," used in the preparation of the book Rah for the Engineers!
  - Chapters I-XII. No Date (Box 2, Folder 8-20)
  - "Academics in the College of Engineering." 1959 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Departmental reports. 1966-1985 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - The Blarney Book. 1954-1969 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Series IV: Monographs, 1986
  Corrected copy of Rah for the Engineers! with handwritten notes by McCormick to future researchers using his history.
  - Monographs. 1986 (Box 2, Folder 24)